{
  "theme": [
    {
      "Questions": [
        {
          "Question": "What is the fictional substance that powers the TARDIS in Doctor Who?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Artron energy",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Plutonium",
            "Unobtanium",
            "Dilithium"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Artron energy is a form of temporal energy used to power the TARDIS time machine in 'Doctor Who.'"
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which actor played Captain Jean-Luc Picard in Star Trek: The Next Generation?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Patrick Stewart",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Harrison Ford",
            "William Shatner",
            "Leonard Nimoy"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Patrick Stewart portrayed Captain Jean-Luc Picard, a central character in 'Star Trek: The Next Generation' from 1987-1994."
        },
        {
          "Question": "In the TV series Stranger Things, what is Eleven's real name?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Jane",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Mary",
            "Sarah",
            "Emma"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The character Eleven, played by Millie Bobby Brown, is revealed to have the real name Jane in the TV series 'Stranger Things'."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which sci-fi series features the tagline 'To Boldly Go Where No Man Has Gone Before'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Star Trek",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "The X-Files",
            "Battlestar Galactica",
            "Firefly"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The tagline 'To Boldly Go Where No Man Has Gone Before' is associated with the iconic Star Trek franchise."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which sci-fi series is set in the 24th century and features the Borg as recurring antagonists?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Star Trek: The Next Generation",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "The Expanse",
            "Fringe",
            "Black Mirror"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Star Trek: The Next Generation is set in the 24th century and features the cybernetic Borg as recurring antagonists."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who is the creator of the science fiction series 'Black Mirror'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Charlie Brooker",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "J.J. Abrams",
            "Steven Moffat",
            "Lena Waithe"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Charlie Brooker is the creator of the anthology series 'Black Mirror', known for its dark and thought-provoking stories set in a dystopian future."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What is the name of the AI system on the spaceship Rocinante in 'The Expanse'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "The Investigator",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "HAL 9000",
            "Cortana",
            "Skynet"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The AI system on the spaceship Rocinante in 'The Expanse' is known as The Investigator, a mysterious and enigmatic presence."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which TV series features a parallel universe known as the 'Upside Down'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Stranger Things",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Fringe",
            "Dark",
            "The OA"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The parallel universe known as the 'Upside Down' is a central element in the sci-fi horror series 'Stranger Things'."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What futuristic device does Rick Sanchez use for inter-dimensional travel in 'Rick and Morty'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Portal gun",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Time machine",
            "Teleporter",
            "Warp drive"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Rick Sanchez, a brilliant but morally ambiguous scientist, employs a portal gun for inter-dimensional travel in the animated series 'Rick and Morty'."
        },
        {
          "Question": "In the TV series 'The Mandalorian', what is the real name of the title character?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Din Djarin",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Jango Fett",
            "Boba Fett",
            "Cassian Andor"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The title character of 'The Mandalorian' is revealed to be Din Djarin, an enigmatic and skilled bounty hunter in the Star Wars universe."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which sci-fi series features the concept of a 'Timey-Wimey' ball of... stuff?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Doctor Who",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "The 100",
            "Lost",
            "The Orville"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The term 'Timey-Wimey' refers to the timey-wimey ball of... stuff, a whimsical concept associated with time travel in 'Doctor Who'."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What is the name of the computer system on the spaceship Serenity in the TV series 'Firefly'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Serenity",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Cortana",
            "Mother",
            "Holly"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The spaceship Serenity in the TV series 'Firefly' is equipped with a computer system named after the ship itself, providing essential functions and guidance."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which sci-fi series follows the crew of the spaceship Bebop as they hunt for bounties?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Cowboy Bebop",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Outlaw Star",
            "Trigun",
            "Space Dandy"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The anime series 'Cowboy Bebop' centers on the adventurous exploits of the spaceship Bebop's eclectic crew as they pursue bounties across the galaxy."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which sci-fi series revolves around a group of survivors aboard the eponymous spaceship searching for a new home?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Battlestar Galactica",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Stargate SG-1",
            "Andromeda",
            "The Expanse"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The series 'Battlestar Galactica' focuses on the remnants of humanity aboard the spacecraft Galactica as they seek a new home after a devastating war."
        },
        {
          "Question": "In 'The Twilight Zone', what serves as a recurring plot device related to moral or ethical dilemmas?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Twists",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Cliffhangers",
            "MacGuffins",
            "Easter eggs"
          ],
          "Explanation": "'The Twilight Zone' is renowned for its unexpected twists, which often serve as a poignant commentary on moral or ethical dilemmas."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What synthetic android model is a central character in the TV series 'Humans'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Anita/Mia",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Data",
            "Cylons",
            "Ultron"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Anita, also known as Mia, is a synthetic humanoid or 'synth' model that becomes increasingly sentient and essential in the series 'Humans'."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which dystopian sci-fi series portrays a society segregated into factions based on personality traits?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Divergent",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "The 100",
            "The Hunger Games",
            "Altered Carbon"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The 'Divergent' series features a society divided into distinct factions, each based on specific personality traits, leading to conflict and rebellion."
        },
        {
          "Question": "In the TV series 'Orphan Black', how many clones are initially revealed to the central character, Sarah Manning?",
          "TrueAnswer": "7",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "2",
            "11",
            "4"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The central character Sarah Manning discovers that she is one of seven genetically identical clones, each with unique personalities and circumstances."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which sci-fi series explores a future where consciousness can be digitized and transferred between bodies?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Altered Carbon",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "The 100",
            "The Expanse",
            "Westworld"
          ],
          "Explanation": "'Altered Carbon' delves into a world where human consciousness can be digitized and transferred between bodies, leading to societal and existential implications."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What is the name of the spaceship piloted by the central character in the TV series 'Star Trek: Discovery'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "USS Discovery",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Serenity",
            "Millennium Falcon",
            "Nostromo"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The USS Discovery is the starship central to the events in 'Star Trek: Discovery', embarking on diverse missions and encounters in the Star Trek universe."
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}